Guide to the Dorotheda Revay Anderson Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Dorotheda Revay Anderson papers
1842-1989
1931-1989
SC0574
Anderson, Dorotheda Revay.
4 Linear feet
This collection largely pertains to Anderson's professional career and includes her curriculum vita, letters of recommendation, clippings, teaching materials, correspondence, photographs, and her reference files on dancers and artists. Correspondents include British dancer Vera Fredova (Winifred Edwards) and Ivor F. Guest. There is also a plaster cast of Victor Frisch's life mask of Anna Pavlova and a framed German notice for a performance of the ballet Gisella, 1842. Other items include clippings, newsletters, and photographs pertaining to tennis, 1950-1988.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of the estate of D. Revay Anderson, 1999.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Dorotheda Revay Anderson, a graduate of the American Academy of Dramatic Arts in New York City, was a member of the Amercan Ballet Theatre from 1951-53. She earned her B.A. in anthropology at Stanford University in 1960 and her M.A. in education in 1961. From 1962 to 1964 she was in charge of ballet and modern dance at UC Berkeley. In 1964 she was appointed professor of dance at California State University, Sacramento and retired in 1988 with the rank of professor emeritus. Prof. Anderson has served as consultant on a national public television series and as juror and panelist for several ballet companies and competitions.
Description of the Collection
This collection largely pertains to Anderson's professional career and includes her curriculum vita, letters of recommendation, clippings, teaching materials, correspondence, photographs, and her reference files on dancers and artists. Correspondents include British dancer Vera Fredova (Winifred Edwards) and Ivor F. Guest. There is also a plaster cast of Victor Frisch's life mask of Anna Pavlova and a framed German notice for a performance of the ballet Gisella, 1842. Other items include clippings, newsletters, and photographs pertaining to tennis, 1950-1988.
Access Terms
Anderson, Dorotheda Revay.; Edwards, Winifred.; Frisch, Victor, 1876?-1939.; Guest, Ivor Forbes.; Pavlova, Anna, 1881-1931.; Ballet dancers.; Dance--Study and teaching--United States.; Tennis.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Biographical clippings (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum vita (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters of recommendation (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Class handout: “Selected Forms, Concepts, and French Terms of the Classic Dance” (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Class materials, California State University, Sacramento: syllabae, tests, handouts, 1982-1983 and undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - CSU, Sacramento: notices and handouts re dance-related events, 1972-79 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Choreography notes (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: letters from Vera Fredova (Winifred Edwards), 1975, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with Ivor Guest, 1975-1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, general (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Memorabilia: autograph book (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous items (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Poems, typescript (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Tennis, clippings and newsletters, 1950-1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Tennis, photographs of Art Larsen (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Brown, Leslie: dancer’s profiles from programs (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Jasperson, Sally: clippings and curriculum vita (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Kosloff (Theodore) / Baldina (Alexandra): photos, clippings, notes (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Massine, Leonine: transcript of interview, 1978, programs, clippings (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Pavlova, Anna: information on the life mask sculpted by Victor Frisch (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Pring, Dorothy: Reváy’s remarks at her memorial service, 1971; advertisement of Pring’s ballet studio (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Tudor, Anthony: clippings, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Artists: biographical information on Richard O’Hanlon and Richard Vincent West (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dancers, miscellaneous: programs, articles, clippings, 1931-1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - [probably Leonine Massine - 2 originals, 2 duplicates], 4 videotapes (.75 inch) (Box 3)
  - Framed diplomas for Reváy’s B.A. (1960) and M.A. (1961) from Stanford (Box 3)
  - Framed certificate to Reváy from American Biographical Institute (Box 3)
  - German notice for performance of the ballet Gisella, 1842 (Box 4)
  - Life mask of Pavlova [plaster cast from original by Victor Frisch] (Box 5)